Finding Aid for Photo and Campus Services (University of Michigan) photographs, 1960-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Photo and Campus Services (University of Michigan) photographs
1960-1987
1969-1970
1980-1984
University of Michigan. Photo and Campus Service.
94135 Bimu 2
The University of Michigan Photo and Campus Services is a comprehensive photographic unit established to meet the needs of the schools, colleges, departments, and other units within the university as well as individuals within the university community. In existence since 1948, the unit officially became part of News and Information Services in 1997. Services include photographic reproduction and studio and location photography.
1.25 linear feet in 2 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Records were received from Photo and Campus Services in 1994 and 1995 (Donor No. 8238 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The Photo and Campus Services (University of Michigan) records are open for research without restriction.
Photo and Campus Services (also known as Photo Services) has been operating as a full-service photographic lab since 1948. In addition to photographic developing and reproduction, the unit also specializes in taking passport photos, portraits and photographing special events. Photo Services staff photographers frequently were contracted by the university's News and Information Services to photograph university events. As a result of this arrangement, many images taken by Photo Services staff are included in the News and Information Services record group. In July 1997, Photo Services officially became a part of News and Information Services.
Several staff photographers had lengthy affiliations with Photo Services, including Bob Kalmbach, who served as chief photographer during a career that spanned more than 45 years until his official retirement in 2000. Kalmbach continued to work after his retirement until his death on February 12, 2001.
Photographer D.C. Goings joined Photo Services in 1974, and performed copy and slide work, location and studio photography, and event coverage, along with print and reproduction work. Goings eventually joined Biomedical Communications and worked with their photographic unit. Paul Jaronski came to Photo Services as a printer under the tutelage of Kalmbach in 1976. He became a staff photographer, and also worked in the areas of black-and-white processing, reproduction, and portraiture.
Since its establishment, Photo Services has maintained a facility in Room B542 in the basement of the LS&A Building on State Street.
Photo Services also maintains a growing archive of color and black-and-white stock shots, including buildings and campus scenes, which are available for publishing needs.
The photographic images in the Photo and Campus Services record group represent a small portion of the images created by the unit. The photographic materials are divided into three series based on format: Slides, Portrait Negatives, and Photographs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Aerial photographs.; Architectural elements.; Auditoriums--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Educational buildings.; Galleries and museums--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Hospitals--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Newcomb, Theodore Mead, 1903-1984.; Pedestrian bridges.; Plazas--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Roads--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.Buildings.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan. Law Library.; University of Michigan--Student housing.Student housing.; University of Michigan. University Hospital.; Schembechler, Bo.; College sports--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Coaches (Athletics)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Portrait photographs.; Slides.
- Slides, 1969-1970
  The series Slides, 1969-1970 (0.2 linear feet), consists of collected color slides of buildings located on the University of Michigan's central and north campuses and in its medical center. The slides include aerial shots and shots taken at close angles. Some slides feature students, buildings under construction, and U.S. Highway 23. A small number of slides feature Theodore Mead Newcomb, who served as professor of human understanding and held joint appointments in sociology and psychology.
  - Aerial Views
    - Central Campus
      - Administration Building (Fleming) and Regents Plaza (Box 1)
      - Angell Hall and Law Quadrangle (Box 1)
      - Hill Auditorium and Surroundings (Box 1)
      - Law Quadrangle see: Angell Hall envelope (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Natural Science Building (Edward Henry Kraus Building) (Box 1)
    - U.S. Highway 23 Interchange (Box 1)
  - Architectural Elements
    - Central Campus
      - Fountain (Box 1)
      - Pedestrian Bridge and Tennis Courts (Box 1)
      - Regents Plaza (Box 1)
  - Buildings
    - Central Campus
      - Dentistry, School of (Box 1)
      - Institute for Social Research (ISR) (Box 1)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts Building (Box 1)
      - Museum of Art (Alumni Memorial Hall) (Box 1)
      - Power Center for the Performing Arts (Box 1)
      - President's House (Box 1)
      - William L. Clements Library and Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library (Box 1)
    - Medical Center
      - C.S. Mott Children's Hospital (Box 1)
      - Henry F. Vaughn Building (School of Public Health) (Box 1)
      - Towsley Center for Continuing Medical Education (Box 1)
      - Upjohn Center for Clinical Pharmacology (Box 1)
    - North Campus
      - Chrysler Center (Box 1)
      - Northwood IV Apartments (Box 1)
      - School of Music (Box 1)
  - Faculty
    - Theodore Mead Newcomb (Box 1)
- Portrait Negatives
  Portrait Negatives, 1979-1987 (0.4 linear feet), illustrates the portraiture work done by the staff photographers. The negatives are divided into two subseries: athletics and non-athletics. Athletics portrait negatives are comprised primarily of 2" x 2" black and white and some color negatives of various coaches and staff including trainers and sports information personnel. All portraits are of individuals with the exception of one joint image of University of Michigan football coach Bo Schembechler with his counterpart from Michigan State University, George Perles. Non-athletics negatives include various faculty and staff members associated with the university.
  - Athletics
    - Agase, Alex (Assistant Football Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Dr. Robert, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Boyd, Michael (Basketball Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Burke, Gregg (Assistant Sports Information Director), 1981; 1982 (Box 1)
    - Bytwerk, Diane, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Canning, Barbara, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Chmiel, Bob (Assistant Football Coach), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Coke, Elizabeth, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Collins, Karen (Field Hockey Coach), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Crall, Martha (Sports Information), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Cusumano, Bill, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Darden, Bob, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Falk, Jon (Equipment Manager), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Farrell, Dan (Hockey Coach), 1977 (Box 1)
    - Fisher, Steve (Assistant Basketball Coach), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Giarmo, Bill (Assistant Football Coach), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Giordano, John, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Goodridge, Francie (Women's Track), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Hall, Danny, (Assistant Baseball Coach)1982 (Box 1)
    - Hammer, David (Basketball), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Hand, Bill, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Healy, Mark (Assistant Athletic Trainer), 1981; 1983 (Box 1)
    - Henry, James (Track Coach), 1982; 1984 (Box 1)
    - Hoey, George (Academic Advisor), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Humphries, Jody (Sports Information), 1987 (Box 1)
    - Hutchins, Carol (Women's Softball), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Hyatt, Sheri (Women's Gymnastics Coach), 1981; 1983 (Box 1)
    - Isaac, Stuart, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Kahler, Paul (Assistant Women's Basketball Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Kempthorn, Dana, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Kimball, Dick (Diving Coach), 1982 (Box 1)
    - LeClair, Sue (Women's Golf Coach), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Lindsay, Peter (Women's Swimming Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Madej, Bruce (Sports Information), 1984 (Box 1)
    - McGuire, Michael, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Milidonis, Mike (Gymnastics Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Miller, Clay, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Miller, Russ (Head Athletic Trainer), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Minert, Don (Assistant Athletic Trainer), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Moeller, Gary (Assistant Football Coach), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Murphy, Gary, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Murray, Mike, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Norman, Debbie, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ocker, Phyllis (Associate Athletic Director), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Palmisano, Michael, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Parks, Sue, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Peal, Sue, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Perry, Pat, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Reed, Laura (Women's Softball), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Rezendez, Maria (Assistant Softball Coach), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ritt, Elizabeth (Women's Tennis), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Rogers, Rick, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ruggles, Greg (Assistant Basketball Coach), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Schembechler, Bo (Football Coach) with George Perles (Michigan State University Football Coach), 1987 (Box 1)
    - Scneider, Jim (Sports Information), 1981; 1987 (Box 1)
    - Soluk, Gloria (Women's Basketball Coach), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Thompson, Rex (Athletic Trainer), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Triveline, Don, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Turner, Mike (Assistant Hockey Coach), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Tweedy, Leon (Stadium Superintendent), 1987 (Box 1)
    - Urbanchek, Jon (Swimming Coach), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Uzelac, Elliot (Assistant Coach Football), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Van De Wege, Bud (Assistant Basketball Coach), 1981; 1984 (Box 1)
    - Vooletich, Milan (Assistant Football Coach), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Walter, Tim, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Wentworth, Pete, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Zagroli, Ro, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Zientek, Candy (Women's Field Hockey Coach), 1979; 1983 (Box 1)
  - Non-Athletics
    - Abd-Allah, Umar, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Bill, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Archie, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Marc, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Banks, Richard, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Bartus, David, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Bayless, Margaret, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Beale, Ruby, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Beckman, Susan, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Bromage, [Arthur], 1982 (Box 1)
    - Brophy, David; Reilly, Raymond, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Alan, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Burn, Reed, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Chmielewske, Jean, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Cooper, Diane, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Cramer, Thomas, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Culherson, Robert B., 1981 (Box 1)
    - Dalke, John, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Degen, Brian, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ebeno, Patrick, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Eckent, Penelope, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Ernsting, Tom, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Faubion, Walter, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Fechtner, Robert, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Fedorowycz, Ihor, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Fry, Rosemary, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Green, Jerrold, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Green, Melissa, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Grey, Sylvia, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Kaufman, Ruth, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Kinning, Kimberly, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Maloney, Bill F., 1984 (Box 1)
    - Martinez, David, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Martinez, David, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Matsunaga, Eiko, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Mullice, Anthony, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Noseda, James, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Oakes, William, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Okley, Deborah, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Peters, Larry, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Poggi, Lisa, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Rocco, Judy, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Rushlow, Eva; Lovasz, Karen, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Scott, Norman R., 1982 (Box 1)
    - Shy, John, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Smith, Brenda, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Smith, Greta, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Smith, Greta, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Stegchnis, Christine, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Steins, Edward, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Stern, Michele, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Stukenhutz, Larry, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Stya, Marga, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Thone, Patricia, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Voss, Kay, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Ward, Frank, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Wayne, Donald, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Wellman, Mary, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Wells, Jan, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Westram, Prof., 1982 (Box 1)
    - Zimmerman, J., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Photo Services Staff
    - Group photo, 1989 (Box 1)
      (with David Hamel (student), Paul Jaronski, Joyce Huff, Virginia Geren, Susan Effinger (student), D.C. Goings, and Pam Sinclair)
- Photographs (outsize)
  Photographs, ca. 1960 and 1970 (0.6 linear feet), are comprised of outsize mounted images. Two images from ca. 1960 show Photo Services staff and equipment. A series of 40 photographs taken in 1970 documents the Law Quadrangle and includes interiors, exteriors, students studying and conversing, and specific architectural details of the Law Quadrangle buildings.
  - Photo Services Staff and Equipment, circa 1960; 2 images (Box 2)
  - Law Quadrangle Series (Interiors, Exteriors, Students, Architectural Details), 1970; 40 images (Box 2)